Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today EnglishPod is in the kitchen.
我是Catherine，今天EnglishPod在厨房里。
That's right. Today we are going to hit the kitchen and we're going to bake a cake.
没错。今天我们要进厨房，烤一个蛋糕。
Alright, so check out this dialogue first and when we come back we'll be talking about some very key phrases and words for cooking in English.
好的，先听一下这段对话，等我们回来后会讨论一些英语烹饪中非常关键的短语和词汇。
Okay, so are you ready to learn how to bake a cake?
好了，你准备好学习如何烤蛋糕了吗？
Almost. Let me just put my apron on.
快了。让我先系上围裙。
Okay, so the first thing we're going to do is preheat the oven.
好的，我们要做的第一件事是预热烤箱。
That way we have it at the desired temperature once we finish preparing everything.
这样等我们准备好所有东西时，烤箱就能达到我们想要的温度了。
Set it to 375 degrees Fahrenheit.
调到华氏375度。
Got it.
明白了。
Now we're going to make the batter.
现在我们要做面糊了。
Take some butter and sugar and mix it lightly until you have a nice consistency.
拿一些黄油和糖，轻轻搅拌，直到质地均匀。
Then add some vanilla extract and eggs and continue mixing.
然后加入一些香草精和鸡蛋，继续搅拌。
Do I have to use the whisk or can I use the electric mixer?
我必须要用手动打蛋器，还是可以用电动搅拌器？
Go ahead and use the mixer, but put it on medium speed.
用搅拌器吧，但调到中速。
I'm going to sift the flour and baking powder separately and then we can mix it with milk and the rest of the ingredients.
我要把面粉和泡打粉单独过筛，然后和牛奶以及其他配料混合在一起。
Okay, so now we need a baking pan, right?
好的，那我们现在需要一个烤盘，对吧？
Yeah, but grease and flour it first so the cake won't stick to it when it bakes.
对，但先涂油撒粉，这样蛋糕烤的时候就不会粘在盘上。
Done. So how long do we bake it for?
搞定了。那我们要烤多久？
We can leave it in there for about 25 minutes.
可以放进去烤大约25分钟。
Then we let it cool for 10 minutes before we remove the cake from the pan.
然后让它冷却10分钟，再把蛋糕从烤盘里取出来。
Wow, this is a lot easier than I thought.
哇，这比我想象的简单多了。
Alright, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those key words on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在来看看“语言小贴士”里的一些关键词。
Language Takeaway
语言小贴士
Well, first of all, we have a special thing to keep our clothes clean while we are cooking.
首先，我们有一个特别的东西，用来在做饭时保持衣服干净。
What is this thing called, Marco?
这个东西叫什么，Marco？
This is called an apron.
这叫围裙。
An apron.
围裙。
So it's not actually a shirt, it's a piece of fabric that you maybe tie around your waist or around your neck to protect your clothes from flour and butter and oil.
它其实不是衬衫，而是一块布料，你可以系在腰上或脖子上，保护衣服不被面粉、黄油和油弄脏。
That's right. So it's very common to wear an apron while you're cooking or maybe while you're cleaning the house or the kitchen in order to avoid getting dirty, like you say.
没错。所以做饭时，或者打扫房子或厨房时，为了避免弄脏，就像你说的，穿围裙很常见。
So we're going to start baking our cake and the first thing that we do is we turn on the oven in order to have it at the desired temperature.
我们要开始烤蛋糕了，第一件事就是打开烤箱，让它达到想要的温度。
Now this is something you might see in a recipe that says the desired temperature is 450 degrees.
这你在食谱里可能会看到，说想要的温度是450度。
So that means the temperature you want to achieve. Maybe when you turn the oven on it's only 100 degrees.
意思就是你想达到的温度。也许你刚打开烤箱时只有100度。
Right.
对。
So you have to wait for the desired temperature, which is what is indicated in the recipe.
所以你得等它达到想要的温度，也就是食谱里指定的温度。
That's right. So this is what we want. We want the desired temperature of 375 degrees.
没错。这就是我们想要的。我们想要375度的温度。
So now we got that done and now we're going to make the batter.
现在这一步完成了，接下来我们要做面糊。
All right. The batter is the liquid, it's the cake, before the cake becomes a cake.
好的。面糊是液体状的，是蛋糕在变成蛋糕之前的状态。
So it's usually like a very thick liquid, like a very thick, almost buttery, milky substance.
它通常是一种很浓稠的液体，非常浓稠，几乎像黄油和牛奶的混合物。
And after you cook it, it turns hard. So batter is the liquid form.
烤熟之后就会变硬。所以面糊是液体形态。
Right. So when you're making a cake, you make batter.
对。所以做蛋糕时，你要做面糊。
Now it's different because if you're making pizza or you're making bread, it's not called batter.
这不一样，因为如果你做披萨或面包，那就不叫面糊了。
No. If you're making pizza or bread, because those are thicker, they're called dough.
不叫。做披萨或面包时，因为那些更厚，所以叫面团。
But when it's still like milk or water, it's like a liquid, we call it a batter.
但如果还是像牛奶或水一样的液体，我们就叫它面糊。
A batter. Very good. So obviously to make the batter, we add sugar, we add butter, we add eggs.
面糊。很好。所以显然，做面糊要加糖、黄油和鸡蛋。
And then what we want to do is we want to mix it. And so the other person asks, well, what do I do?
然后我们要做的就是搅拌。所以另一个人会问，那我该怎么做？
Do I have to use a whisk or an electric mixer?
我必须要用手动打蛋器还是电动搅拌器？
All right. These are two very important tools that you will find in most kitchens.
好的。这是大多数厨房里都会有的两个非常重要的工具。
A whisk is like a spoon, but it's made of metal and it's empty inside.
手动打蛋器像勺子，但它是金属做的，中间是空的。
And we use it for things like eggs or milk and sugar. And it can go very, very quickly.
我们用它来搅拌鸡蛋、牛奶和糖之类的东西。它可以搅得很快很快。
It makes a kss, kss, kss, kss sound, like a whisk sound.
它会发出“嘶嘶嘶嘶”的声音，就像打蛋器的声音。
Yeah, it's like a wire all around it.
对，它周围都是金属丝。
Yeah, it's wire that's woven together. And so it's a very, very handy tool, but you only use one hand to use it.
对，是编织在一起的金属丝。这是一个非常方便的工具，但只用一只手就能操作。
But an electric mixer is what the name says. It's electric. You plug it in and it does the whisking automatically.
而电动搅拌器，顾名思义，是电动的。你插上电，它就会自动搅拌。
That's right. All right. So this is what we want to use.
没错。好的。这就是我们要用的。
And before we put the batter into the baking pan, what we want to do first is we want to grease and flour the sides of the baking pan.
在把面糊倒进烤盘之前，我们首先要给烤盘的内壁涂油撒粉。
So then, you know, it won't stick.
这样它就不会粘了。
All right. So to grease something means to use oil or butter to make sure that the meat or the dough does not stick later.
好的。所以“涂油”就是用油或黄油，确保肉或面团之后不会粘住。
That's right. So you can even use it for, obviously, in cooking terms, if you put butter or something like this,
没错。在烹饪术语中，你可以用黄油之类的东西，
but even grease, like the black grease, maybe you need to put it in your door because maybe it's making that weird sound.
但“grease”也可以指黑色的润滑油，比如你可能需要把它涂在门上，因为门发出奇怪的声音。
Right. So to grease something is to add oil or to add butter in order to keep something from sticking.
对。所以“涂油”就是加些油或黄油，防止东西粘住。
That's right. OK. So a lot of words there. Now, why don't we pass on to some phrases?
没错。好了，词汇不少。现在我们来看看一些短语吧。
Let's start with some fluency builder.
先从“流利表达”开始。
Now, at the beginning of the dialogue, we talked about the oven.
在对话开头，我们提到了烤箱。
The real phrase you're going to see in a cookbook is preheat the oven.
你在食谱里真正会看到的短语是“预热烤箱”。
That's right. So we have the prefix there, pre, to preheat something.
没错。这里有个前缀“pre-”，表示“预先加热”。
And that means to begin or to start heating.
意思就是开始加热。
Now, this is because when I turn my oven on, right, Marco, it's not 450 degrees.
这是因为，Marco，当我打开烤箱时，它并不是450度。
It takes some time to become hot.
需要一些时间才能变热。
So we preheat the oven. We turn it on before we need it in order to make sure it's ready when we do need it.
所以我们预热烤箱。在需要之前就打开它，确保真正需要时它已经准备好了。
That's right. So you're going to see it in every recipe. If you're baking something, you need to preheat the oven.
没错。你在每个食谱里都会看到。如果你要烤东西，就需要预热烤箱。
And now when we were actually mixing some of the things, we came up on this interesting phrase when we said we need to sift the flour and the baking powder.
然后在我们搅拌一些东西时，遇到了一个有趣的短语，我们说需要过筛面粉和泡打粉。
All right. Now, these are both white substances. They're soft.
好的。这两种都是白色粉末，很细腻。
They're dry. And sometimes they are. They're bumpy. They have lumps in them.
它们是干的。有时会有结块，凹凸不平。
So we need to make sure that there are no lumps.
所以我们需要确保没有结块。
And we have a special tool that will help us sift the flour and sift the baking powder.
我们有一个专门的工具来帮助过筛面粉和泡打粉。
So it's like a wire mesh tool. And you rotate the handle. You turn the handle.
它是一个金属网工具。你旋转手柄。
And it will flatten out this flour so that there are no more bumps. It's all smooth.
它会把面粉弄平，不再有结块，变得很光滑。
OK. I think I've heard it also when they're talking about gold, right?
好的。我好像也听过他们谈论金子的时候用过这个词，对吧？
Don't they say that they were sifting for gold in the rivers?
他们不是说在河里淘金吗？
That's right. Well, you have a tray and you shake the tray to make sure the small gold falls down, but the big, the chunks stay on top.
没错。嗯，你有一个托盘，然后你摇晃托盘，确保小金块掉下去，但大块的、成块的留在上面。
That's the same idea. Yeah.
道理是一样的。是的。
OK. So that's what we're doing here. We're sifting the flour and the baking powder.
好的。这就是我们现在做的。我们在筛面粉和泡打粉。
And now we put our cake in the oven and we ask, well, so how long do we bake it for?
现在我们把蛋糕放进烤箱，然后问，嗯，我们要烤多久？
And we say, well, we can leave it in there for about 25 minutes.
我们说，嗯，我们可以把它放在里面大约25分钟。
So the phrase here, to leave it in, means to keep the cake in the oven.
所以这里的短语“leave it in”意思是把蛋糕留在烤箱里。
And this is something we can say about a lot of things.
这个说法可以用在很多事情上。
So maybe the turkey that we're cooking is in the oven. It's been in the oven for four hours.
比如，也许我们正在烤的火鸡在烤箱里。它已经在烤箱里烤了四个小时了。
And I look at it and I say, is it ready yet? My mom says, no, leave it in. Leave it in.
我看着它问：好了吗？我妈妈说：不，让它继续烤。让它继续烤。
So that means don't take it out. Keep it in the oven. Leave it in.
所以意思是别拿出来。让它留在烤箱里。让它继续烤。
So we don't really need to say leave it inside the oven or we don't need to be too specific.
所以我们不需要说“leave it inside the oven”，或者不需要说得太具体。
We can just say leave it in. Keep it cooking. Keep it cooking. That's right.
我们只需要说“leave it in”。继续烤。继续烤。没错。
OK. So let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
好的。那我们最后再听一遍对话。
OK. So are you ready to learn how to bake a cake?
好的。你准备好学习如何烤蛋糕了吗？
Almost. Let me just put my apron on.
快了。让我先穿上围裙。
OK. So the first thing we're going to do is preheat the oven.
好的。我们要做的第一件事是预热烤箱。
That way we have it at the desired temperature once we finish preparing everything.
这样，等我们准备好所有东西时，烤箱就已经达到想要的温度了。
Set it to 375 degrees Fahrenheit.
调到华氏375度。
Got it.
明白了。
Now we're going to make the batter.
现在我们要做面糊。
Take some butter and sugar and mix it lightly until you have a nice consistency.
拿一些黄油和糖，轻轻搅拌，直到质地合适。
Then add some vanilla extract and eggs and continue mixing.
然后加入一些香草精和鸡蛋，继续搅拌。
Do I have to use the whisk or can I use the electric mixer?
我必须要用打蛋器，还是可以用电动搅拌器？
Go ahead and use the mixer, but put it on medium speed.
用搅拌器吧，但调到中速。
I'm going to sift the flour and baking powder separately
我要把面粉和泡打粉分开筛一下。
and then we can mix it with milk and the rest of the ingredients.
然后我们可以把它和牛奶以及其他配料混合。
OK. So now we need a baking pan, right?
好的。那我们现在需要一个烤盘，对吧？
Yeah, but grease and flour it first so the cake won't stick to it when it bakes.
是的，但先涂油撒粉，这样蛋糕烤的时候就不会粘在上面。
Done. So how long do we bake it for?
做好了。那我们要烤多久？
We can leave it in there for about 25 minutes.
我们可以把它放在里面大约25分钟。
Then we let it cool for 10 minutes before we remove the cake from the pan.
然后让它冷却10分钟，再把蛋糕从烤盘里取出来。
Wow. This is a lot easier than I thought.
哇。这比我想象的简单多了。
So baking a cake seems easy enough.
所以烤蛋糕看起来挺容易的。
Now maybe there are some other things that we can add that we didn't mention.
现在也许还有一些我们没提到的可以加的东西。
Like, for example, vanilla extract. It's mentioned in the recipe.
比如，香草精。食谱里提到了。
So that is a liquid, right?
所以那是液体，对吧？
It's a liquid. It's a flavor.
是液体。是一种调味料。
So extracts are used to give different foods flavors.
所以提取物用来给不同的食物增添风味。
You can have orange extract and vanilla extract.
你可以有橙子提取物和香草提取物。
Vanilla comes from a bean, a brown bean.
香草来自一种豆子，一种棕色的豆子。
They take the oil from this plant and that's what gives things like cake a vanilla flavor.
他们从这种植物中提取油，这就是给蛋糕之类的东西带来香草味的东西。
Now what about this baking pan?
那这个烤盘呢？
This is specifically for cakes.
这是专门用来烤蛋糕的。
Now what if you're making something like muffins? Is it also called a baking pan?
那如果你做的是像松饼之类的东西呢？它也叫烤盘吗？
No, you'd have a muffin tin or a muffin pan.
不，你会有一个松饼模具或松饼盘。
And so those are a different shape.
那些形状不一样。
They're round. They're circular.
它们是圆的。是圆形的。
They're made of that tin material.
它们是用那种锡材料做的。
They're not very heavy and they can go in the oven and not break.
它们不是很重，可以放进烤箱而不会破裂。
But normally we have a baking sheet which is flat.
但通常我们有一个平的烤盘。
Or a baking pan which would be for a cake pan.
或者一个烤盘，那是用来做蛋糕盘的。
It's got sides on it.
它有边。
And we have a muffin tin which is for muffins.
我们有一个松饼模具，是用来做松饼的。
And what we didn't mention is we actually have our cake
我们没提到的是，我们实际上有蛋糕。
but then there's something that we always add on top of the cake or all over the cake.
但还有一样东西我们总是加在蛋糕上面或整个蛋糕上。
Yeah, well not always but most cakes, at least most tasty cakes, have frosting.
是的，嗯，不总是，但大多数蛋糕，至少大多数好吃的蛋糕，都有糖霜。
So that's something that you add after the cake has finished cooking.
所以那是蛋糕烤好之后加的东西。
That's right. So frosting is like a cream or something that you add around the cake.
没错。所以糖霜就像奶油之类的东西，你加在蛋糕周围。
It's actually just sugar and water.
实际上只是糖和水。
Sugar and water. Oh really?
糖和水。哦，真的吗？
You can add milk if you want to make it thicker.
如果你想让它更稠，可以加牛奶。
But when I make frosting, I like to make it from scratch.
但当我做糖霜时，我喜欢从头开始做。
That means I make it by myself.
意思是我自己做。
I use water and powdered sugar.
我用水和糖粉。
Powdered sugar. And then you mix it.
糖粉。然后你搅拌它。
You mix it. You whisk it.
你搅拌它。你搅打它。
And then you get the frosting.
然后你就得到糖霜了。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
And well, maybe this recipe is actually real.
嗯，也许这个食谱是真的。
Although we didn't give the amounts, the quantities.
虽然我们没有给出用量、数量。
But maybe you can try baking a cake and let us know how it goes.
但也许你可以试着烤一个蛋糕，然后告诉我们结果如何。
Or maybe you can give us a cake recipe.
或者也许你可以给我们一个蛋糕食谱。
That's right. Our website is EnglishPod.com.
没错。我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you guys there.
我们希望在那里见到你们。
All right. Bye.
好了。再见。
♪♪♪